

HAYMAN MOHAMMED

Date of Birth: 2 May 1989 Nationality: Iraqi/Kurdish

Gender: Male

Marital Status: Single

Email: hayman.salih@diag.uniroma1.it Telephone Number: +39 (393) 025-1989

Permanent Address: Via Catania 1, Guidonia Montecelio RM / Italy.

PROFILE

I worked in several local and international companies in Kurdistan for more than 6 years. During this time I got many professional expertise in the field of Information Technology, Networking, Website Management, Traffic Engineering (QoS) and Computers Maintenance. My professional and academic background enabled me to deal with the complex issues and solve them with compatible standards.

EDUCATION

PHD IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Sapienza University of Roma (Rome, Italy)
PhD Candidate, Department of Computer, Control and
Management Engineering "Antonio Ruberti" 2017-Until Now

MASTER IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Eastern Mediterranean University (Famagusta, Cyprus) Master's degree, Computer Engineering, 2012 – 2014

Thesis Title: A Comparative Study on Palmprint Recognition **Supervisor:** Ass. Prof. Dr. Onsen Toygar

BSC IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

University of Picardie Jules Verne UPJV (Amiens, France) Bachelor of Computer Science (BSc), 2006 – 2011

Graduation Project: Local Network Management, Design and Implementation

EXPERIENCE

REMOTE NETWORK OPERATOR

Cellnet TELECOM (January 2017 - September 2018)

- Designing stable and reliable Wireless network.
- Provide professional network topology and diagram for stable internet service.
- Establish Wireless network with UBNT, MIKROTIK products.
- Installation and configuration PTP & PTM UBNT Mikrotik infrastructure of the wireless and their complex connectivity and redundancy connectivity between all base stations with big capacity of bandwidth stable connectivity between all base stations.
- Installation configuration UBNT devices, Air Fiber Rocket Dish, Sectors and directional sectors.
- Mikrotik products Wireless base stations base box with antenna router board 1100 and CCR cloud Router 1036 their installation configuration for deferent requirements filtering bandwidth controller
- failover load balancer redundancy hotspots wireless DHCP BGP
- Configuration Broadband and Hotspots infrastructure and the Radius authentication.
- PRTG installation for monitoring network stability and bandwidth usage.

EXPERIENCE

NOC SENIOR ENGINEER

Alsardfiber (January 2015 - December 2016)

- Serve as primary responder for all server issues and customer complaints, monitoring the progress of events and supplying the client, partner or vendor with updates.
- Monitor all of the global edge cast servers, applications, network devices and connections along with customer traffic, using specific custom built tools.
- Work with the system and network administration teams to resolve complex issues within specific service level agreement times
- Work directly with edge cast customer to resolve technical issues and questions.
- Provide thorough research of customer facing issues and provide report escalation teams prior to escalation.
- Update customers regularly on ongoing trouble tickets and provide full report issues.
- Applying updated solutions for the internal issues.
- Daily bandwidth calculation for each customer independently.
- Installation and configuration of point to point networks (Rockets, Nanostations, Airfiber and other Ubnt devices).
- Checking the main fiber optic cores incase of having any outage and determining the distance of outage by using OTDR.
- Writing nightly reports of all activities and solved issues during the night working hours.

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Eastern Mediterranean University (September 2013 - October 2014)

- Providing technology assistance to the department.
- Maintain staff workstations and peripherals, including applying and updating virus detection software, and multimedia applications.
- Applying system tools for management staff.
- Troubleshoot software and hardware problems on staff equipment.
- Performing equipment repairs as necessary.
- · Performing other duties as assigned

IT/NETWORK ENGINEER

Teknokar Co. (April 2011 - September 2012)

- Handling VSAT hub/technical escalations and resolving issues
- Monitoring region operations directly and remotely on installation coordination, providing solutions to regions on technical escalations.
- Negotiate prices with satellite providers
- Prepare monthly bandwidth reports for all hubs and discuss and advise management.
- Installing, supporting and maintaining new server hardware and software infrastructure;
- Setting up user accounts, permissions, and passwords;
- Monitoring network usage;
- Analyzing and resolving faults, ranging from a major system crash to a forgotten password;
- Providing training and technical support for users with varying levels of IT knowledge and competence;
- Supervising other staff, such as help-desk technicians;
- Presenting company to potential clients through direct communication in face to face meetings, telephone calls and emails
- Troubleshooting system and network problems and diagnosing and solving hardware or software faults;
- Maintenance of network infrastructure and architecture
- Maintain a thorough understanding of the basics behind the Internet and its workings (DNS, Security, IP Routing, HTTP, VPN, Email Routing, SPAM, etc.

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

Digital Image Processing, Design Patterns, Java, Matlab, C++, C, Microsoft Office, Windows, HTML, IT Management, IT Solutions, Project Management, Marketing, Multimedia, Wireless Communications Systems, Wireless Networking, Systems Analysis, Data Mining, Statistics, Cisco Technologies, Artificial Intelligence.

LANGUAGUES

KURDISH Native or bilingual proficiency

ENGLISH Full professional proficiency

ARABIC Full professional proficiency

TURKISH Professional working proficiency

INTERESTS

Reading, Traveling, Digital Photography, Listening to Music, Watching Movies.

NOTES

- I certify that the above information is true, complete, and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief. Otherwise I'll undertake all consequent results.
- I'm ready to provide you all documents, papers, and certifications, which support the above statement
- References are available upon request